Fistfights over a flat-screen TV, hours in a queue for cookware, arguments over air-fryers.
为了抢一台平板电视大打出手，为了买炊具排队数小时，为了空气炸锅争吵不休。
Why is it that discounts and deals can turn a simple shopping trip into a rampage through a retail park?
为什么折扣和优惠能让一次简单的购物之旅变成在零售园区里的疯狂行为？
What is it that makes a bargain so irresistible?
是什么让便宜货如此令人难以抗拒？
The answer might be in our heads.
答案可能就在我们的大脑里。
An fMRI study, where brain activity is measured, has shown that when we think about money we might spend, brain areas sensitive to pain are activated.
一项测量大脑活动的功能性磁共振成像研究表明，当我们想到可能要花的钱时，对疼痛敏感的大脑区域会被激活。
When we think about the thing that we want to buy, areas sensitive to pleasure are triggered.
当我们想到想买的东西时，对愉悦敏感的区域会被触发。
Our medial prefrontal cortex evaluates these responses and makes a decision.
我们的内侧前额叶皮层会评估这些反应并做出决定。
If it looks like a good deal, we're more likely to make the purchase and get a hit of dopamine.
如果看起来很划算，我们就更有可能购买并得到一剂多巴胺。
Writer Mark Elwood, who has written a book all about bargains, tells us that we get even more dopamine from something that's unexpected, such as when something is surprisingly cheap.
作家马克·埃尔伍德写了一本关于便宜货的书，他告诉我们，意想不到的东西会带来更多的多巴胺，比如某样东西出人意料地便宜。
Our brains are keen to reward us for finding bargains and many shops are keen to take advantage of this.
我们的大脑热衷于奖励我们因为发现了便宜货，许多商店也热衷于利用这一点。
Anchoring is a pricing strategy where we are shown an initial price, and then the real one.
锚定是一种定价策略，先向我们展示一个初始价格，然后再展示真实价格。
Popular items may be positioned next to something much more expensive, or we may see a very high previous price, next to the heavily reduced one currently available.
热门商品可能会被放在更昂贵的商品旁边，或者我们会看到商品有一个非常高的原价，旁边则是大幅降价后的当前价格。
The initial price, or anchor, conditions how we evaluate what something actually costs.
初始价格，或称锚点，会影响我们评估某物实际成本的方式。
Inflated anchor prices can make unreasonably high actual prices seem fair, and our brains are happy to reward us when we make the purchase.
虚高的锚点价格会让实际上不合理的高价显得合理，而我们的大脑在我们购买时会乐于奖励我们。
Other strategies include time limits, threatening to deprive us of our dopamine hit if we're not quick enough, and charm pricing, where we're much less worried about paying £9.99 than £10.
其他策略包括时间限制（威胁说如果我们不够快就会剥夺我们的多巴胺快感）以及魅力定价（我们支付9.99英镑比支付10英镑时焦虑要少得多）。
If we know this about how our brains work and how retailers might act, what should we do?
如果我们知道我们的大脑是如何工作的，以及零售商可能会如何行动，我们应该怎么做？
It can be useful to take time to consider what we're buying, hold on to something and walk around the shop before buying to give ourselves more time to evaluate a potential purchase.
花时间考虑我们要买什么，在购买前拿着东西在店里转转，给自己更多的时间来评估潜在的购买行为，这可能会很有用。
It can also be sensible to research prices before shopping, to get a better idea of what represents good value.
在购物前调查下价格，更好地了解什么才是划算的价格，这也是明智之举。